MAN:
Kids, I'm gonna tell you
an incredible story;
the story of how
I met your mother.
Are we being punished
for something?
No.
Yeah, is this gonna
take a while?
Yes. 25 years ago,
before I was Dad,
I had this whole other life.
It was way back in 2005.
I was 27, just starting
to make it as an architect
and living in New York
with Marshall,
my best friend from college.
My life was good.
And then Uncle Marshall went
and screwed the whole thing up.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Perfect!
And then you're engaged.
You pop the champagne.
You drink a toast.
You have sex
on the kitchen floor.
Don't have sex
on our kitchen floor.
Got it.
Thanks for helping me
plan this out, Ted.
Dude, are you kidding?
It's you and Lilly.
I've been there
for all the big moments
of you and Lilly:
night you met,
your first date,
other first things.
Yeah, sorry.
We thought you were asleep.
It's physics, Marshall.
If the bottom bunk moves,
the top bunk moves, too.
My God.
You're getting engaged tonight.
Yeah.
What are you doin' tonight?
What was I doing?
Here Uncle Marshall was taking
the biggest step of his life.
And me?
I'm calling up
your Uncle Barney.
Hey, so you know
how I've always had a thing
for half-Asian girls?
Well, now I've got
a new favorite-- Lebanese girls.
Lebanese girls
are the new half-Asians.
Hey, you want
to do somethin' tonight?
Okay, meet me at the bar
in 15 minutes. And suit up!
Hey.
Where's your suit?
Just once,
when I say suit up,
I wish you'd put on a suit.
I did that one time.
It was a blazer!
You know,
ever since college
it's been, Marshall
and Lilly and me.
Now, it's gonna be
Marshall and Lilly...
and me.
They'll get married,
start a family.
Before long,
I'm that weird,
middle-aged bachelor
their kids call
Uncle Ted.
I see what this is about.
Have you forgotten
what I said to you
the night we met?
Ted, I'm gonna teach
you how to live.
Barney.
We met at the urinal.
Oh, right. Right.
Lesson one:
lose the goatee.
It doesn't go
with your suit.
I'm not wearing a suit.
Lesson two: get a suit.
Suits are cool.
Exhibit "A."
Lesson three:
don't even think
about getting married
till you're 30.
30. Right.
You're right.
I guess it's just,
your best friend
gets engaged,
you start thinking
about that stuff.
I thought I was
your best friend.
Ted, say
I'm your best friend.
You're my best
friend, Barney.
Good. Then,
as your best friend,
I suggest we play
a little game
I like to call
"Have you met Ted?"
Wait. No, no, no.
We're not playing
"Have you met Ted?"
Hi, have you met Ted?
Hi,
I'm Ted.
Yasmine.
That's a very pretty name.
Thanks. It's Lebanese.
Hey.
( sighs )
I'm exhausted.
It was finger-painting day
at school,
and a five year-old boy got
to second base with me.
Wow! You're cooking?
Yes, I am.
Aw...
Are you sure
that's a good idea?
After last time, you looked
really creepy without eyebrows.
I can handle this.
I think you'll
find I'm full of
surprises tonight.
So, there's more surprises?
Likewhat?
Marshall was in his second year
of law school,
so he was pretty good
at thinking on his feet.
Boogedyboo!
And that's all of 'em.
I'm gonna go... cook.
I'm so happy for Marshall,
I really am.
I just couldn't imagine
settling down right now.
So, do you think
you'll ever get married?
Well, maybe eventually...
some fall day,
possibly in Central Park.
Simple ceremony.
We'll write our own vows.
Band, no DJ.
People will dance!
I'm not gonna worry
about it!
Damn it, why did Marshall
have to get engaged?
Yeah, nothing hotter
than a guy planning out
his own imaginary wedding, huh?
Actually,
I think it's cute.
Well, you're clearly drunk.
One more for the lady!
Oh, hey,
look what I got.
Oh, honey! Champagne.
Yeah.
No. You are too old to be scared
to open a bottle of champagne.
I'm not scared.
Then open it.
Fine.
Please open it?
You are unbelievable,
Marshall.
There are two big questions
a man has to ask in life.
One, you plan out for months.
The other just slips out when
you're half drunk at some bar.
Will you marry me?
You wanna go out
sometime?
Of course, you idiot!
I'm sorry,
Carl's my boyfriend.
'Sup, Carl?
( both sigh )
I promised Ted
we wouldn't do that.
Did you know
there's a Pop Tart
under your fridge?
No, but dibs.
Where's that champagne?
I wanna drink a toast
with my fiancée.
Oh!
I don't know why
I was so scared of this.
It's pretty easy, right?
Oh!
( Lilly shrieks )
Why am I freaking out
all of a sudden?
This is crazy.
I'm not ready
to settle down.
How does Carl land
a Lebanese girl?
The plan has always been
don't even think about it
until you're 30.
Exactly. The guy doesn't
even own a suit.
Plus, Marshall's found
the love of his life.
Even if I was ready,
which I'm not...
but if I was,
it's, like,
"Okay, I'm ready. Where is she?"
( romantic music plays )
And there she was.
It was like something
from an old movie,
where the sailor sees the girl
across the crowded dance floor,
turns to his buddy and says,
"See that girl?
I'm gonna marry her someday."
Hey, Barney,
see that girl?
Oh, yeah. You just know
she likes it dirty.
Go say hi.
I can't just go say hi.
I need a plan.
I'm gonna wait
until she goes
to the bathroom,
then I'll strategically place
myself by the jukebox...
Hi, have you met Ted?
Hi.
Let me guess...
Ted.
Sorry, Lilly.
I'm so sorry.
Take us to the hospital.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Did you hit her?
( both laugh )
Hit me? Please!
This guy can barely
even spank me in
bed for fun.
He's all like, "Oh, honey.
Did that hurt?"
And, I'm like,
"Come on!
Let me have it,
you pansy!"
Wow, a complete stranger.
No, no, no, no! It's okay.
Go on.
So, these,
uh, spankings...
you in pajamas
or au naturel?
So, what do you do?
I'm a reporter
for Metro News One.
Oh.
Well, kind of a reporter.
I do those dumb
little fluff pieces
at the end of the news.
You know, like, um...
monkey who can play
the ukulele.
I'm hoping to get
some bigger stories soon.
Bigger, like, uh...
gorilla with an upright bass?
Sorry.
You're really pretty.
( laughs )
Oh, your friends
don't seem to happy.
Yeah, see, the one
in the middle just
got dumped
by her boyfriend.
So, tonight, every guy
is "the enemy."
You know if it'll make
your friend feel better,
you could throw a drink
in my face. I don't mind.
She would love that!
And it does look
fun in the movies.
Hey, you wanna have dinner
with me Saturday night?
Oh, I can't.
I'm going to Orlando
for a week on Friday.
Some guy's attempting to make
the world's biggest pancake.
Guess who's covering it?
That's gonna take a week?
Yeah, he's gonna
eat it, too.
It's another record.
Hey! What's takin' so long?
Uh, I know this
is a long shot,
but how 'bout tomorrow night?
Yeah. What the hell?
Jerk!
That was fun.
De... wait for it...
nied!
Denied!
We're goin' out
tomorrow night.
I thought we were playin'
laser tag tomorrow night.
Yeah, I was never gonna
go play laser tag.
The next night,
I took her out
to this little bistro
in Brooklyn.
Wow! That is one badass
blue French horn.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Sort of looks
like a Smurf penis.
Son, a piece of advice:
when you go on a first date,
you really don't wanna say
"Smurf penis."
Girls don't
ordinarily like that.
But this was no ordinary girl.
( laughing )
Lilly?
( table clatters )
How long have
you been sitting there?
Stupid eye patch.
Mom, Dad,
I have found
the future Mrs. Ted Mosby.
Marshall, how have I always
described my perfect woman?
Now, let's see...
she likes dogs?
I've got five dogs.
She drinks scotch?
I love a scotch
that's old enough
to order its own scotch.
Can quote obscure lines
from Ghostbusters?
Ray! When someone asks you
if you're a god, you say "Yes!"
And I'm saving
the best for last.
Do you want these?
I hate olives.
She hates olives! Awesome!
The olive theory.
The olive theory
is based on my friends
Marshall and Lilly.
He hates olives,
she loves them.
In a weird way,
that's what makes
them such a great couple.
Perfect balance.
You know, I've had
a jar of olives
just sitting
in my fridge forever.
I could take 'em
off your hands.
They're all yours.
Oh, it is on!
It is on
( singing ):
till the break of dawn.
But wait.
It's only the break of 10:30.
What happened?
I gotta get one
of those blue
French horns
for over my fireplace.
It's gotta be blue.
It's gotta be French.
No green clarinet?
Nope.
Come on.
No purple tuba?
It's a Smurf penis
or no dice.
( laughs )
WOMAN:
There you are!
We got a jumper.
Some crazy guy
on the Manhattan Bridge.
Come on. You're coverin' it!
Um... all right.
I'll be right there.
I'm sorry.
I had a really
great time tonight.
Yeah.
So?!
Did you kiss her?
No. The moment wasn't right.
Look, this woman
could actually be
my future wife.
I want our first kiss
to be amazing.
Aw, Ted, that is so sweet.
So you chickened out
like a little bitch.
What? I did not chicken out.
You know what?
I don't need to take
first kiss advice
from some pirate
who hasn't been single
since the first week of college.
Anyone who's single
would tell you
the same thing,
even the dumbest
single person alive.
And if you don't believe me,
call him.
( rock music playing )
Hey, loser.
How's not playing laser tag?
Because playing
laser tag is awesome!
Oh, I killed you,
Conner!
Don't make me
get your mom!
Hey, listen.
I need your opinion
on something.
Okay, meet me
at the bar in
15 minutes.
And suit up!
So, these guys
think I chickened out.
What do you think?
I can't believe you're
still not wearing a suit.
She didn't even
give me the signal.
What, is she gonna, she gonna
bat her eyes at you
in Morse code?
"Ted...
kiss me."
No! You just kiss her!
Not if you don't
get the signal.
Did Marshall
give me the signal?
No!
I didn't. I swear.
But, see,
at least tonight,
I get to sleep knowing
Marshall and me,
never gonna happen.
You should have kissed her.
Oh, I should have kissed her.
Well, maybe in a week when
she gets back from Orlando.
A week? That's like
a year in hot girl time.
She'll forget all about you.
Mark my words-- you will
never see that one again.
There she is.
Ooh! She's cute.
Hey, Carl, turn it up.
...persuaded him to reconsider.
At which point,
the man came down
off the ledge,
giving this bizarre story
a happy ending.
Reporting from Metro One News...
Huh.
Guy didn't jump.
I'm gonna go kiss her.
Right now.
Look, dude.
It's midnight.
As your future lawyer,
I'm gonna advise you
that's freakin' crazy.
I never do anything crazy.
I'm always
waiting for the moment,
planning the moment.
Well, she's leaving tomorrow.
This may be
the only moment I'm gonna get.
I gotta do what
that guy couldn't.
I gotta take the leap!
Okay, not a perfect metaphor,
'cause for me it's fall
in love and get married,
and for him it's... death.
Actually, that
is a perfect metaphor.
By the way, did I
congratulate you two?
I'm doing this.
Let's go.
Word up.
We're coming
with you.
Barney?
All right,
but under one condition.
Look at you, you
beautiful bastard.
You suited up!
This is totally
going in my blog!
Stop the car.
Uh, pull over
right here.
I gotta do something.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Just a sec'.
Enjoy your coffee.
Hey!
Go! Go! Go!
Everybody
brings flowers.
( exhales )
Okay.
Moment of truth.
Wish me luck.
Ted's gonna get it on
with a TV reporter.
"This just in." Okay.
Kiss her, Ted!
Kiss her good!
Kiss the crap
outta that girl!
Marshall, remember this night.
When you're the best man
at our wedding
and you give a speech,
you're gonna tell this story.
Why does he get
to be the best man?
I'm your
best friend!
As I walked up to that door,
a million thoughts
raced through my mind.
Unfortunately, one particular
thought did not.
I've got five dogs.
( doorbell buzzes, barking )
Not good. Not good.
Not good. Not good. Not good.
No!
Get back in there!
You're wearing
a suit!
( barking continues )
Ted?
Hi.
I was just, uh...
Come on up.
MARSHALL:
He's in.
So...
Ranjit, you must have done
it with a Lebanese girl?
Okay, that's
my Barney limit.
I'm gonna see if that bodega
has a bathroom.
Actually,
I'm from Bangladesh.
The women hot there?
Here's a picture
of my wife.
A simple "no" would
have sufficed.
She's lovely.
So, Ted,
what brings you back
to Brooklyn
at 1:00 in the morning
in a suit?
I was just hoping to...
get those olives...
that you said I could have.
Would you like those olives
with some gin and vermouth?
Are you trying to get me drunk?
For starters.
( romantic music plays )
So, Marshall,
this olive theory,
based on you and Lilly?
Yeah.
You hate olives.
Lilly loves 'em.
You can't stand 'em.
Yeah. Hate olives.
Two weeks ago, Spanish bar
on 79th street,
dish of olives, you had some--
what up?
You have to swear that this
does not leave this cab.
I swear.
On our first date,
I ordered a Greek salad.
Lilly asked if she
could have my olives.
I said, "Sure. I hate olives."
But, you like olives.
Well, I was 18, okay?
I was a virgin.
Been waitin' my whole life for
a pretty girl to want my olives.
Marshall, I'm gonna give you
an early wedding present.
Don't get married.
♪ Baby, since I met you, oh... ♪
I think I like
your olive theory.
your new French horn.
I think I like your nose.
I think I'm
in love with you.
What?!
What?
Come on, man,
you said your stomach's been
hurting. You know what that is.
Hunger.
You're hungry for experience.
Hungry for something new.
Hungry for olives.
But you're too scared
to do anything about it.
Yeah, I'm scared,
okay?
But, when I think
of spending
the rest of my life
with Lilly--
committing, forever,
no other women--
doesn't scare me at all.
I'm marrying that girl.
Lilly.
Lilly, I like olives.
We'll make it work.
Aw...
So, Orlando.
You gonna
hit Disneyworld?
You love me?!
I-I-I can't believe
I said that.
Why did I say that?
Who says that?
I should just go.
Hold on.
Wait a minute.
Promised you these.
Olives.
Yeah.
Thanks. I love you.
What is wrong
with me?
Why are we still
sitting here?
Let's go. We can still
make last call.
What do you say, Lil?
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum?
'Cause you're a pirate.
Okay, eye patch, gone.
And we can't just
abandon Ted.
If it doesn't go well up there,
he's gonna need some support.
It's been,
like, 20 minutes.
You think they're doin' it?
You think they're doin' it
in front of the dogs?
Doggy style.
( laughing )
Hey, there was
a girl in college,
she had this golden
retriever...
Okay, we can go to the bar.
Just stop talking.
Hit it, Ranjit.
So, when you tell
this story to your friends,
could you avoid
the word "psycho?"
I'd prefer... "eccentric."
Good night... psycho.
Great.
Um, how do I get to the F train?
Oh, um, two blocks
that way and take a right.
You know what?
I'm done being single.
I'm not good at it.
Look, obviously,
you can't tell a woman
you just met you love her.
But...
it sucks that you can't.
I'll tell you something, though.
If a woman-- not you, just some
hypothetical woman--
were to bear with me
through all this,
I think I'd make
a damn good husband.
Because, that's
the stuff I'd be good at,
stuff like making her laugh
and being a good father.
And walking her five
hypothetical dogs.
Being a good kisser.
Everyone thinks
they're a good kisser.
Oh, I've got references.
Good night, Ted.
And I'm a good handshaker.
That's a pretty
great handshake.
And that was it.
I'll probably
never see her again.
What?
That was the signal.
That long,
lingering handshake?
You should have kissed her.
There's no such thing
as "the signal."
But, yeah,
that was the signal.
Signal.
Ah, Carl,
thank you.
Something
I gotta do.
By the way,
you should have kissed her.
Carl!
You guys weren't there.
( cork pops )
I am so turned
on right now.
TED:
Guys, trust me.
I've seen the signal.
That was not the signal.
Yeah, Ted, we're
not on you anymore.
To my fiancée.
To the future.
To one hell
of a night!
That was not the signal.
I asked her
about it years later.
And, yeah, that was the signal.
I could have kissed her.
But that's the funny
thing about destiny.
It happens
whether you plan it or not.
I mean, I never thought
I'd see that girl again,
but it turns out I was just
too close to the puzzle
to see the picture
that was forming.
Because, that, kids,
is the true story of how
I met your Aunt Robin.
Aunt Robin?
I thought this was
how you met mom!
Will you relax?
I'm getting to it.
Like I said, it's a long story.